Antique Comb Collectors Club (AC3) Records
Antique Comb Collectors Club (AC3) Records
1985-2001
Antique Comb Collectors Club (U.S.)
3.5 linear ft.
Correspondence, publicity, board materials, membership lists, etc. for the Antique Comb Collectors Club (U.S.)
5388757
Biographical History
The Antique Comb Collector's Club (AC3) was formed in 1985 by Betty Miller and Doris Eff to enable those interested in antique combs and hair ornaments to exchange information and research, and share their passion for these collectible items. Betty also owned The Miller Comb Museum, which operated out of her home in Homer, Alaska and housed more than 3000 artifacts. The club's first convention was held in Florida in 1993. The club was active until 2013.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Antique Comb Collectors Club (AC3) Records consists of the retained records of the club. To preserve contextual information, and to retain the club's original filing scheme, material has been left in original folders with original labels. Unfoldered material found in the boxes was foldered and assigned a title based on content; these titles are given in the inventory below in square brackets [...]. Folders have been grouped into logical series as follows: board material, convention material, correspondence, publicity, records, and miscellany. Empty archival folders have been inserted as series identifiers/dividers.
Board material includes minutes, notes, correspondence and other material.
Convention material relates to the club's international convention, held in 2001.
Correspondence with prospects contains correspondence with prospective members. As such it often includes descriptions of the club and its activities.
Correspondence, general contains correspondence with members. Some is arranged alphabetically and some chronologically, as received. There is also a folder labeled "Unfiled correspondence." There is a good deal of correspondence with collector-authors Belva Green, Mary Bachman, and Jen Cruse.
Publicity includes discussions of how to publicize the club and attract new members, as well as correspondence regarding book reviews, advertisements, presence at various meetings and conferences, and clippings.
Records contains two folders explicitly labeled as such. They contain membership lists and some financial/expense information.
Miscellany contains membership cards and a videotape.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection remains largely as received, in original folders with original labels. Folders have been grouped into logical series, as described above, and within that arranged in rough chronological order. Material inside each folder has been left as received. Material found to be unfoldered was assessed and grouped with the series where it seemed the best fit.
Related Material
Numerous issues of the club's newsletter, Antique Comb Collector, have been cataloged. Please refer to to locate these items. A small amount of related material may be found in the
Antique Comb Collector's Club (AC3) Collection
.
has numerous other collections with sketches, designs and other items related to hair combs. Please for "combs" to see a full listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Plastics; Bachman, Mary.; Beall, Glenn.; Cruse, Jen.; Eff, Doris, 1917-; Green, Belva.; Miller, Betty, 1933-; Antique Comb Collectors Club (U.S.); Antique Comb Collectors Club International.; Hair ornaments -- Collectors and collecting.; Ornamental combs -- Collectors and collecting.; Ornamental combs -- Societies and clubs.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Financial records.; Membership lists.; Minutes (administrative records); VHS.; Videocassettes.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Betty Miller, 2019.
Inventory
- Board material
  - ACCC Board, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Board ACCC, 1995-1996 (Box 1)
  - ACCC Board, 1996-1998 (Box 1)
  - Corresp AC4 Board and Bachman, various constitution drafts, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Board meetings [and] convention, 2000 (Box 2)
- Convention material
  - Convention program, 2001 (Box 2)
- Correspondence with prospects
  - Corresp misc (Prospects), 1987-1991 (Box 2)
  - ACCC prospects correspondence current year, 1999-2000 (Box 2)
  - [Prospects?], 2000; material was unfoldered and placed here based on content (Box 3)
- Correspondence, general
  - [Correspondence A-F], 1989-1992 (Box 3)
  - ACC Member Corresp A thru F, 1988-1997 (Box 3)
  - ACCC Member Corresp G-K, 1992-1997 (Box 3)
  - Corresp L-P, 1992-1997 (Box 4)
  - Corresp R-Z, 1990-1997 (Box 4)
  - J. [Jen] Cruse, 1993-1998 (Box 4)
  - [Correspondence], 1994 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence ACCC, 1994 (Box 5)
  - Unfiled Member Corresp, 1992-1998 (Box 5)
  - ACCC Member Corresp current year, 1999 (Box 5)
  - [Correspondence], 2000-2001; 2 folders (Box 5)
- Publicity-related material
  - Publicity, directories, listings, media, misc. related associations, courtesy exchanges, 1987-1998 (Box 6)
  - ACCCI current year correspondence, directory response, misc internet auctions and searches, 1999-2000 (Box 6)
  - Publicity PR, circa 2000 (Box 6)
- Records
  - ACCC Records, 1987-1997 (Box 6)
  - ACC Report, budget & finance, 1990-2002 (Box 6)
  - [Membership cards], 2 small boxes containing index cards with member information (Box 7)
- Miscellaneous
  - Belva Green's PAX-TV network show "Treasures in your Home", 2001; accc_records_001; "Treasures in your Home" was a series on PAX-TV, hosted by John Burke. It ran for 200+ episodes. This episode features Belva Green, an expert on antique hair combs. Recording of television broadcast.; VHS (Box 7)
  - [Miscellaneous items], undated; mostly printed, including ACCC and Miller Comb Museum brochures, paste-up for flyer, three rosters, color photocopies of two photographs of the Miller Comb Museum in Alaska (Box 6)